Roberto Serra

Full Stack Engineer

e: obi.serra@gmail.com
g: https://github.com/obiSerra
l: https://www.linkedin.com/in/obiserra/

m: 338-6414351

Personal Profile

I am a web developer with near 10 years of experience; during those years I worked as a freelance, consultant and employee, having the opportunity to work with startups as wellas creatives collective and enterprise companies

Work

Senior Software Engineer

Experiences

Sept 2014 - Present

Designing and developing enterprise and large scale modern web applications for the US and European markets.

Tech: AngularJS, React, Clojure, RabbitMQ, MongoDb, Jenkins, Groovy

Full Stack Developer

Dec 2008 - Aug 2014

Developer and consultat for web agencies

Tech: Third Party API integration, PHP, JavaScript, HTML5 Canvas

Web and Mobile Developer

Jan 2012 - Aug 2014

Developing and designing web applications, mobile apps (PhoneGap and Titanium) and HTML5 games.

Tech: Yii, PHP, MySQL, Javscript, ¡Query

Co-founder and Developer

Mar 2010 - Dec 2011

Developing web sites and web applications for small and medium sized companies

Tech: WordPress, Joomla, PHP, HTML, CSS, JavaScript

PHP Developer

Mar 2010 - Dec 2011

Developing and maintaining a live auction web application

Tech: PHP, HTML, CSS, JavaScript

Notable Projects

- An animated interactive YouTube Masthead for a famous italian fashion house
- A quoting web application for a US assurance company
- A car configurator for top a multinational automotive company
- A management tool for massive live tournaments for a US gaming company
- Two multiplatform mobile applications
- A real time auction web application
- Many web applications for startups

Key Skills

JavaScript, CoffeeScript, ClojureScript, TypeScript

PHP, Clojure, Python, Bash Script AngularJS, React, Backbone, Angular4

Luminus, MODx, Yii, Laravel

MySQL, MongoDb

Git, bash, ssh, Unix, Jenkins, CI Good attitude to work with teams

Good experience as project and team leader

Education

Università degli Studi di Torino

Laurea in Scienze Della Comunicazione - Bachelor of Arts in Communication Studies